how do you look up the source of a web
page and there's a lot of fun things you
can do with this in fact there's a a
scene in Mr Robot where Elliot
reminisces about when he used to be able
to go back and look at the source code
of a web page and you can just copy it
out and save it and steal it and make it
your own and let's talk about how to do
that right now so um and it doesn't have
to be anything really very fancy um if
you can go so here's this websockets you
could go to even the skill stack page
skill stack. we'll go out there and um
so here we are we're on
skill. and all you need to do is right
click you may know this already and you
can do view page Source if you want to
see the actual source code which you can
copy and paste into something of your
own um or you can just right click and
do uh inspect now I imagine most of you
out there the Curious among you have
already figured out how to do this this
is not particularly hackery I am kind of
dressed like hacker or quintessential
hacker today but um it's it's not
particularly hackery but there is a
there are a couple situations where this
can be very valuable um and I I do want
to show you some of the fun so the
obvious first reason to do inspect
element is to just kind of understand
how a web page is composed and let me
show you how that will work out when
we're doing live development so so here
I am in vs code I have a web page that
is really not a web page I just put you
know something in here just to make a
point uh whoops here we go did I switch
back did I switch back yeah you guys
back okay so so anyway here you go
you're looking at the web page here and
I don't know if you can see if you can
kind of highlight over everything and
it'll show you exactly thing there's a
lot of stuff there um but the the the
other method here is is to actually work
on a web page
um and then down here we've already did
talked about this in a different video
this is a live server video you can
click on this and that will load it up
into its own web server being served on
the website 127.0.0.1 which means your
computer um and that Port 5500 and there
you see there it is right and if you
right click on this you'll see it's it's
quite a bit simpler right now in my case
I made sure to put it on dark I have
dark reader extension on so that I
didn't blind you like I did in the
another video but as you can see dark
reader added a bunch of classes here to
change the colors and everything but the
most important pieces right there are in
the body of something I can actually
change this I can change it just to uh I
can like double click on it and change
it to something else and you can have
all kinds of fun with this actually um
for example you could go to the
government White House
uh I have to be careful
here because there used to be a porn
site at White house.gov uh it was
something similar to that so I mean I
who I this is dating this video but
that's okay I used to always make fun of
this um but you can actually have a lot
of fun with this you can inspect this
element and say um you know I look
people like I I don't I don't I'm not
this isn't a political video I'm just
going to have no matter who the
president is here I would have fun with
it right so I can go over here and I can
double click on this and it says remarks
by President Biden right and I could say
I could say something like uh
president um let's actually change it
wait why isn't it changing why why you
no work all right let's close this one
move this one
over I mean you the point is I want you
to experiment with stuff so I'm trying
to have fun with it I'm trying to get to
that one store on global variable it's
not letting me change the value for some
reason in this case it should just let
me double click it all right so now here
we can go like this we can
say uh we could say uh
Biden
uh let's
see Biden
says hello I'm trying to be nice here
and you click on something else and you
see how
it uh oh wow okay so there was like
there was something else going on here
let's actually just delete this one Al
together how about that so so there you
just click off of it say it says byen
says hello and then you could actually
change the picture here uh and all kinds
of stuff like that but one of the really
cool things I want to show you this is
one of the most Junior hacks uh that you
could ever do and and I'm going to I'm
going to show you how to do that right
now so uh in order to do this I have to
be really careful um um if you do this I
mean notice by the way if you close this
up if you close up inspect element
notice that nobody nobody sees on the
web page that it's been changed I have a
story about that I have a very I have a
very bad story about this I almost don't
want to tell you I'm going to tell you
anyway um I taught this to somebody and
they told me how they use this technique
to pull up the
grades from I I think I may have talked
about this in another video but they
they use this to pull up the
grades uh from the school website the
internal School website and to show
their their their mom in this case um
their grades and before their mom came
into the room to see the grades they
inspected element and they changed all
their
grades and then they closed inspect
element so that their mom
saw a web page and didn't know that the
grades had been changed and it never
occurred to them that their trusting
young child would not would change those
grades um and this this person confessed
this to me and I was like you make sure
you go tell her what your actual grades
are I felt really bad because I was like
because if that ever came out that I
taught them how to do that and that they
were you know taking advantage of people
who didn't know better um this is really
scary because you can actually take an
existing so like by by the way if you if
if this is a way to troll people right
because you can take you can go to any
like news agency site or any site
whatsoever and you can click on the
stuff that you want and you can change
it to say whatever you want and then you
can take a screenshot and you can put
the screenshot in Twitter or something
and you can say see look at this and 90%
of the people seeing that are never
going to know that you manipulated the
site but the site will otherwise look
like it's exactly the same so yeah it's
a way to troll and to do meing and all
that other stuff and um oh got scrubbed
that's too bad we're not talking about
that please stay on topic on my stream
while I'm making videos um so anyway if
you want to do that that's how you do
that um if you do want to mock up the
website if you want to mock up changes
somebody's website that is one way to do
that as well um but there is actually
one last very very very nefarious very
dangerous thing you can do with this and
the reason I'm putting this in this
video right now is because there's so
many people who don't know that this can
be done okay this is so important so let
me show you what I mean um you can
actually go to any website that has a
password that's been OB confiscated and
you can't hack the password so let's
actually make one I'm not going to do
this to any site at all um and this
works for anything in any web browser um
avoid this by pressing F5 yeah but most
most most people will not know to do
that okay so so let's make a form and
we're going to we're going to give it uh
you guys don't we haven't we're going to
talk about this later but I'm just going
to do it really quickly today um in fact
we don't even need to be a part of a
form we can just put input type equals
password
right um equals
password and and uh name
equals um uh something I mean this is
just the only reason I'm doing this is
just to show you uh form input data it's
like you can put uh enter your password
here right and um let's go ahead and
preview that so we'll go back to our
preview page where where is it where is
it I might have to click it
again I don't remember where it is
um oh I I I can I can go to it I I lost
it but I go it again so it's
127 192 sorry
19 uh no no no no
no where is it Local
Host is it 5050 I can't remember
I can't remember okay so it's down here
click on this port 5500 Clos server okay
let's reopen it I guess because I'm lame
and I can't remember all right there it
is 5500 what did you say okay so here's
our password right so you can say uh my
super secret
password okay so this is what I'm trying
to tell you okay so you ever you ever
come back to a site have you ever have
you ever opened up the web browser that
somebody else was using maybe it was a
maybe it was in a library
maybe it was a multi-user system right
and so somebody for some stupid reason
clicked on Save they clicked on save to
save the form data right or there's a
million reasons but the form data has
been stored in the web browser locally
uh or maybe maybe you have somebody over
your shoulder right maybe somebody
doesn't think they need to um secure
their their desktop PC because oh you
you can't see it it's a bunch of periods
it's a bunch of dots right so here's
here's one scenario so you're working
with somebody they enter their password
in really quickly they don't have any
any Security on their computer at all
and they go get Cofe or something you
just get on the computer and you do this
you right click on this inspect element
and you change the type from password to
text and you click off of it and you can
see their password don't forget to
change that back if you do that by the
way so you double click it on here and
then you tape it tape it back to
password and boom you got their password
you sit back down they don't even know
that you looked at the password that
they
entered that is extremely easy it's one
of the easiest hacks you can do to
anybody and if you social engineer them
and make them have a reason to get out
of the
room it's very very easy to do that um
so many people think that that those
dots save them and I'm trying to tell
you whether this be for your local like
like if you go I don't even want to show
you this one I I I really don't want to
show you this one um I'm not going to
show you this one but if you know how to
access if you're on an internal Wi-Fi
network and you know how to access the
router dashboard if you know what the IP
address is and I'm not going to tell you
that you should know it if you know how
to access that thing you can go onto
that and because it'll give you a web
prompt you might you might be able to
right click on it while they're out of
the room and look up the admin password
for their
router and if you have this if you have
the serial number for the router which
you can easily just write down while
they're out of the room you've got
access to their
entire network their entire home
network um you saw people entering
password that dangerous acts like that
entering passwords and log into the OS
they running and
yeah so I mean this this without saying
right so not to mention the fact that so
many people use the same password for
everything so if you find out what
somebody's password is and you use it
and you're able to get it like really
quickly this where you could use it
anywhere so now you know now you know
just how dangerous this is please please
please don't be owned by anybody and if
you're going to own somebody own
responsibly all right that's all so
there are lots of other reasons to use
inspect element the most important of
them uh of course is to be able to see
how something is done so for example um
let's end on a more a less nefarious
note here um the main reason that we do
inspect element um is to look up uh
these these elements so see how there's
an HTML element and then there's a head
element and then there's a body element
right so by looking at that we're going
to use that in a bit you can see that
even though uh a document that does not
define those things which is 100% valid
HTML 5 um those things will be added by
the web browser and that is also part of
the specification so if you don't know
how a web page is being done you can
always inspect element and you can get
to understand you can understand how
this stuff is working it's very valuable
you can actually do amazing things with
JavaScript which we will not cover right
now but that is the best way for you to
to learn about stuff and I want to end
with one last story okay so this story
happened this is a true story um the
uh School District that shall not be
named decided that they were going to
buy
software uh there they bought software
that included quizzes and online tests
that contained the answers as hidden
Fields uh inside of the HTML so let me
show you what I mean by that they had
input with type equals
um and they would have um name equals U
answer uh value equals something secret
right and this is a true story um some
School District that shall not be named
and shall forever be
shamed um decided that they would buy
software from a company that chose to
hide the answers to the test in plain
text as hidden
fields and as you can see if if you're
just taking the test here you know
there'd be a question to the test and
the answer would be there right they
didn't even obfuscate it they didn't
obsc means they would have changed it to
be something else like you know Bas 64
or even rot 13 they didn't do any of
that they they just made it that answers
and because of this tremendous snapo any
kid who wanted to see the answers to
that question could rightclick on it
inspect element and they could see the
answer to the to that question right
there and the smart kids did do that and
it goes without saying that that this
completely idiotic School District
banned inspect element from every single
browser in the entire School District
rather than own up to this mistake
million dollar mistake or whatever how
much money they spent for this they
actually said you cannot inspect element
on any computer that any of our students
use and I love telling that story
because the number this video has two
things two messages the main message is
if you want to learn how to do web
development learn inspect element
because it's one of the best ways to
learn web
development including if you're working
for a school district that doesn't know
about inspect element and number two
don't you know do stupid things in your
inspect El in in to in your software in
your professional software because you
should expect everything to be inspect
element that that entire School District
had to eat crow and try to stop people
from inspecting element and and they
shut down the number one method for
learning HTML which is just look at the
source which is really sad so hopefully
that gives you some fun things to play
with be good out there though